José Antonio López Domínguez

Contact Information

Objective

email: antonio.lopezd@esimez.mx

Country: Mexico

mobile phone: +52 55 69 65 98 15

Highly skilled Android Engineer with 8+ years of experience in developing high-impact applications, seeking a challenging role to help build applications that enhances the way millions of users interact with it.

Professional Summary

8+ years of experience in Android software engineering, focusing on application analysis, design, development, and testing. Strong understanding of Scrum and Agile methodologies. Proficient in Java, Kotlin and various other technologies and frameworks. Experience in developing a diverse range of applications for various industries, including finance, telecommunications, and manufacturing. Solid understanding of both native and hybrid frameworks. Commitment to staying up-to-date with the latest advancements in frameworks and design patterns.

Technical Skills

- Languages: Java, Kotlin, Python, Dart, TypeScript, JS, C/C++
- Frameworks/Libraries: Android SDK, Flutter, Angular, OpenGL, ARCore, OpenCV, Gradle, NDK
- Tools: Android Studio, Git, Docker, Jenkins, Bash scripts
- Other skills: ReactiveX (RxJava, RxKotlin), Mobile threading, Dagger, CI/CD, MVVM, MVP, TDD, BDD.memory management, data structures, algorithms, computer vision, AI concepts, encryption, user data privacy

Soft Skills

Independent and self-motivated

- Excellent communication skills
- Ability to take leadership in projects
- Fast learner and adaptable
- Creative problem solver and risk-taker

Languages

- Spanish (native speaker)
- English (Upper-Intermediate)

Career History

CourtAvenue, Marketplace - Senior Software Engineer Android/Flutter developer - (Native and Flutter specialist)

May 2023 - present

- Developed and maintained complex Flutter features for marketplace app.
- Collaborated with cross-functional teams to design, implement, and optimize new UI elements, screens, and user flows.
- Integrated RESTful APIs and state management solutions (e.g., Provider, Bloc) to ensure seamless data flow and app responsiveness.
- Stayed abreast of Flutter updates and best practices to continuously improve app performance, stability, and user experience.

Globant, Entertainment - Senior Software Engineer Android/Flutter developer - (Native and Flutter specialist)

March 2021 - May 2023

- Worked on an application used by 5 million users monthly.
- Collaborated with product owners and design teams to develop new features and improve product team efficiency.
- Implemented service-driven development for the application.
- Developed Flutter plugins and apps for both Android and iOS platforms.
- Worked on Augmented Reality projects using ARCore on Android and OpenGL.

Globant, Delivery App - Software Engineer Android developer

June 2020 - Feb 2021

- Developed new features for an app used by 10 million users across Latin America.
- Collaborated with design teams to improve user satisfaction and simplify the user experience in the delivery process.
- Implemented and optimized location-based features to enhance user experience and simplify delivery for more than 500 thousand mobile phone orders per day.

Globant, Point of Sale (POS) - Software Engineer Android developer

Oct 2019 - June 2020

- Fixed numerous bugs and improved performance in a kiosk application.
- Enhanced accessibility services for people with special needs.
- Implemented a service-driven approach to customize the UI.

Grupo Salinas - Software Engineer Android developer

May 2019 - Oct 2019

- Worked on the main app with over 10 million downloads.
- Collaborated with design teams and product owners to add new app functionalities.
- Helped clients streamline the payment process for monthly or recurrent payments.

IBM servicios profesionales S.A. de C.V.- Software Engineer Android developer

Nov. 2016 - May 2019

- Developed a CV implementation for digital document processing, reducing processing time from 2 hours to 15-30 minutes.
- Independently designed, developed, and created a multimedia app for displaying promotions and commercials with service-driven data.

Atisoft S.A. de C.V.- NET Developer

June 2016 - Nov. 2016

Experienced in programming and coding .NET applications Skilled in programming and coding web applications, including experience in JavaScript and related web development technologies.

Education

Instituto Politécnico Nacional, CDMX, México

Aug. 2010 - June 2014

BS, Communications and electronic Engineering

Instituto Politécnico Nacional, CDMX, México

Aug. 2014 - June 2016

MS, Mechanical Design (Robotics) - Honorable Ment